Android最强大的特性之一就是
One of the most powerful features of Android, since the
自这个平台发布以来
start of the platform has been the ability to deliver
就有及时通知用户的能力
timely notifications to users. We're going to add a simple
我们来给天气应用添加一个简单的通知
one to our weather app. This simple notification will show the
这个通知将显示天气预报的图标，文本
weather icon for the forecast, the forecast text, and the
以及今天的高温和低温
high and low temperature for the day. One of the key
我想特别指出的是
things we wanted to point out is how not to
怎么不会把我们的通知变成垃圾
be spammy with our notification. Our app will display at most
我们的应用最多只会显示一个通知。通知过多
a single notification. It really wouldn't make sense if these
排起长队真的没有什么意义。它们也没有足够的内容显示了
notifications stacked up anyhow. They don't display enough information to
通知的关键是提供一个有用的少量的信息
give context. The key thing with notifications is to deliver
并且以一种标准的方式格式化
a useful morsel of information, formatted in a standard way, so
这样它可以与系统其它的通知协调
that it harmonizes with the rest of the system. We'll
我们将首先添加一个字符串
start by adding a string for the preference for the
这个字符串在最后我们会把它通知给用户
last time we sent a notification to the user. As
一个格式化的字符串作为通知的内容
well as a format string for the body of the notification.
让我们实现通知的内部同步适配器
Let's implement the notification inside of our sync adapter.
我们的通知将会基于数据库中的内容
Our notification will be based upon what is in
因此,我们将在同步适配器里
the database. So, we'll create projection and column indices
为天气id创建列索引值
value in our sync adapter, for the weather id. Description,
描述为max 和 min TEMP
max and then temperature, let's add a function to
让我们开始添加函数吧
notify us of the weather. We'll add some additional
我们要增加一些常量。一天的毫秒数
constants up here. One for day in mili's and
以及一个相同的通知ID
one so that we an use the same notification ID.
重用通知ID意味着我们的应用只会有
Reusing the notification ID means that our application will only
最多一个通知。最后我们在同步适配器
post at most one notification. And then finally, we'll call
执行同步数据的函数里，在适当的位置调用
this function at a reasonable place within our on perform
这个函数。
sync function within our sync adapter. Inside of notify weather, we'll
我们会查看是否我们已经显示了那天的通知
check to see whether or not, we've actually shown notification
如果没有，我们得检查数据库
that day. If we haven't, then we'll talk to the database.
获取当天数据解析器的游标
Get a cursor for the current resolver for the current
然后更新数据，但还有一件事没做
day, and then fetch the data, but one thing were not
就是真正的显示出通知。现在好了
doing is actually showing the notification. Now all right, were getting near
我们接近完工了。实现天气的通知
the end. Implement a weather notification,
用Notification Compat.builde创建一个Notification实例
build our notification using Notification Compat.builder
指向V4兼容包的Pending Intent
pointing to a Pending Intent built by the v4 compatible. TaskStackBuilder and
TaskStackBuilder，并且使用NotificationManager发送。
sent with the NotificationManager. Hint: an
提示，显式intent是一个不错的主意
explicit intent to our main activity is
这里有你想读的一些文档
a good idea here. There's lots of documentation on this you'll want to read.